# KARA EVANS

kara.e177409@gmail.com · <u>LinkedIn</u> · <u>Portfolio</u> Cleveland, Ohio | *Open to hybrid & remote roles*.

### **SUMMARY**

Data analyst with more than nine years of professional experience with a focus in laboratory data analysis and application of problem-solving skills. Notable achievements include reducing departmental deviation reports by 20% within the first year of assignment and improving the laboratory inventory program resulting in cost savings and limited workflow disruptions for the organization. Adaptable and able to rapidly acquire new skills. Consistently takes on the role of training and educating fellow employees, contributing to team development and growth.

Skills: SQL, Tableau, Python, Statistical Analysis

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Optometric Technician, Dr. Jodi Rowson & Associates | January 2023-present

• Record patient data and schedule appointments using electronic health record system.

## Senior Technologist, Cleveland Cord Blood Center | November 2017-December 2022

- Evaluated risk of unexpected outcomes, conducted thorough investigations, and produced comprehensive investigative reports using Title 21 Quality Management System. Consistently exceeded goal for report submissions by 400%.
- Maintained detailed inventory records with systematic tracking of supply counts, product information, and expiration dates to ensure optimal inventory control and regulatory compliance.
- Documented laboratory data in Microsoft Excel and CordSource, a web-based application designed for the storage and tracking of clinical data related to cellular therapy products.
- Led and collaborated within a small team to evaluate and present laboratory data, contributing to the formulation of the company's strategic objectives.

# Laboratory Technician, Cleveland Clinic | September 2015-November 2017

- Recorded patient data and monitored specimen location status using laboratory information management system.
- Resolved issues related to patient samples ensuring timely resolution and effective communication to hospital staff.

## Analyst, CWM Environmental | August 2014-September 2015

• Performed environmental analyses on industrial waste samples while adhering to client-specific deadlines.

#### EDUCATION

## Data Analytics Certificate, CareerFoundry | December 2023

Online-based program concentrated on data analysis techniques using industry-standard tools such as SQL, Tableau, and Python. Topics include data quality measures & transformation, statistical hypothesis testing, and visualizations.

Bachelor of Science, Biological Sciences, Ohio University | May 2014 Certificate in Environmental Studies, Ohio University | May 2014